<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Madhu's Blog</title>
    <description>Madhu's Blog</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/test/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/test/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jun 2019 06:43:45 +1000</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 11 Jun 2019 06:43:45 +1000</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.8.5</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Self-judgement defines who you are</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Remember the time when you did something and people were like “Nah, that doesn’t look right..”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Those are the moments that teaches us where we are, or how we are looked upon by others.
I’ve recently read an article about adaptability which taught me a thing or two and I would like to share my points to my readers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I know I have zero readers now, but this article is not written for today, its written for the future. If you think about it all things are written for future, so why not shake hands with my future readers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Its not the organisms that are intelligent that survives, its the most adaptable to the environment.
 - Charles Darwin&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Coming back to the point, in all those judging moments either you might have thought “Who the hell is he to judge me?” or “Shit I’ve done something bad” or “I’m worthless for doing such a thing”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The things that come to your mind may range from “I’m gonna take this advice and keep working on my self to be better” to “I feel like shit. Why am I still living?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The confrontation you have with yourself defines your adaptability. And this adaptability along with self-judgment defines who you are.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;its-hard-and-i-hear-ya&quot;&gt;Its hard and I hear ya&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I know life is super hard, its not easy to bounce back every time that someone judges you.
But listen to yourself for a moment, if you dont feel good about yourself then no one will&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;fall-hard-but-make-sure-you-fall-on-a-bed&quot;&gt;Fall hard but make sure you fall on a bed&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Its ok to fail. Its ok to make mistakes. Its ok to cry about it. But its not ok keep on dwelling about it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Always have a rejuvenation mechanism to come back from it. For me I have the wind as my helper, I chose this because its ubiquitous.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let me know yours in the comment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To your success,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Madhu&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 06 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/test/self-judgement-defines-who-you-are/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/test/self-judgement-defines-who-you-are/</guid>
        
        <category>judgement</category>
        
        <category>self-judgement</category>
        
        <category>suicidal-thoughts</category>
        
        
        <category>You</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Getting high binge watching</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Yes you heard it right. Studies have shown that binge watching releases dopamine as if you getting high on heroine or having sex.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It does feel right after a long day of work, to come home or during the public transport, turn on Netflix and watch an episode of The Big Bang Theory or whatever your favourite series is and enjoy it with a glass of beer or wine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But here’s what does it do to our brain:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;man-of-steel&quot;&gt;Man of Steel&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As it turns out binge watching acts like a steel door blocking all thoughts and concerns we have about something and let us immerse ourselves into the show we are watching. It provides a temporary relief from all the stress, anxiety and depression we face.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;no-discrimination&quot;&gt;No Discrimination&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our body does not discriminate against pleasures we have either by drinking a beer or having a good laugh with friends or working out in the gym or having a runner’s high.
It simply gets addicted to whatever we throw at it. And binge watching is an easy win for it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;wishful-identification-and-parasocial-interaction&quot;&gt;Wishful Identification and Parasocial Interaction&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When we binge, we immerse ourselves in the world of what we watch. eg) Game of Thrones.
we associate our selves with the characters we watch and become a part of them.
We wish we were one of the characters we see and expect things to happen us in the same way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;mourning&quot;&gt;Mourning&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When the series is finally over we mourn over &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;the loss&lt;/code&gt; of connection we had with it.
After sometime it will be replaced with another series and another and this cycle goes on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-good-thing&quot;&gt;The Good thing&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One good thing about binge watching is, if we find some virtual role models in the show, we do what they do. 
So if we were to find a stoic hero who goes through a lot to get what he wants in life, we accept that life is tough and begin to act like that hero.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;binge-watching-responsibly&quot;&gt;Binge watching responsibly&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Binge watching may not be a bad thing if we learn to use it wisely. Example, if one were to begin a startup, &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Shark Tank&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Silicon Valley&lt;/code&gt; would be something good to watch, as they depict the reality of a startup.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Humans learn by observing, and having the digital media filled with lots of good videos is a good thing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;just-make-sure-to-turn-off-when-you-feel-like-just-one-more-episode&quot;&gt;Just make sure to turn off when you feel like &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;just one more episode&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/test/getting-high-binge-watching/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/test/getting-high-binge-watching/</guid>
        
        <category>binge-watching</category>
        
        <category>addiction</category>
        
        
        <category>You</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What's holding you back is not You but You</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I know the title seems confusing, but hear me out&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everyday we wake up, do some chores, get dressed, start to work or do whatever we feel like.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This basic feeling of &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Self&lt;/code&gt; is something that is ingrained in us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We look at the world as how we want the world to be and not as it is. And because of &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Self&lt;/code&gt; imposition on the world, we fail to understand the underlying facts and figures about the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The question is not about whether we can change our view on the world or not.
It’s about whether we accept the facts as it is and move on to do what we destined to do in this world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Destiny is whole other debatable topic in itself, I’m not gonna get into the details of it in this post.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I know the feeling of consuming a lot of self-help content. I get it, it makes you feel good. Hell, it makes you feel like you are on the top of Mount Everest screaming your lungs out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But the reality is, you just keep on consuming and consuming and run around in the same circle once you used to be. And ultimately you become a &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Self Improvement Junkie&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Self Improvement Junkie is a person who keeps on consuming Personal Development Content and fails to take action&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;feel-good&lt;/code&gt; nature of good content, makes us addicted to it, more like chained to it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-can-you-do-to-improve&quot;&gt;What can you do to improve?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;take-action&quot;&gt;Take Action&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hear ya, everyone says the same thing, from Tony Robbins to Tim Ferris. But taking action is hard, really, really hard.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Or is it?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Self&lt;/code&gt; imposition I am talking about. Whether it is hard or not it depends on us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;is-that-all-that-you-are-trying-to-say&quot;&gt;Is that all that you are trying to say?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No. Absolutely not. I don’t wanna list out somethings that you can do to improve yourself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m just gonna tell you one thing. &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Take a deep breath and do it.&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s it. Whatever you are trying to do, that article you were trying to write once, that program you were smashing your brain on, that laundry that you were about do today, whatever it is, just &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Take a deep breath and do it.&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m gonna stop right here and let you make your move.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 23 May 2019 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/test/whats-holding-you-back-is-not-you-but-you/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/test/whats-holding-you-back-is-not-you-but-you/</guid>
        
        <category>self-improvement</category>
        
        <category>self</category>
        
        <category>holding-back</category>
        
        
        <category>You</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>My First Post</title>
        <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Dreams - the bridge between our subconscious and reality&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This blog started as a result of dream I had. In the dream a close friend of mine says, “Something is written on your forehead”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was written &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;எழுதப்பழகு&lt;/code&gt; a combinations of two words in &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tamil_language&quot;&gt;Tamil&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;It is said that all words in a particular language cannot be translated into other without losing a part of the meaning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So the closest translations I can offer you are &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Learn to write&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Make Writing a Habit&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m convinced that this manifestation, is my desire to share the things I always wanted to, hoping this will transform 
into something big in the future&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But honestly, I neither have any idea of what this all means nor I’m aware of where this path will take me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All that I’m willing to do, is give writing a try …&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 22 May 2019 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/test/my-first-post/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/test/my-first-post/</guid>
        
        <category>first-post</category>
        
        
        <category>first</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Design Pattern - Strategy</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;It’s been five years since I had my first Android phone, and today was the day it all changed. No I didn’t get an iPhone, I broke my phone after an accidental drop.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m pretty sure we all have dropped our phones at least once, but only when it falls at the right angle do we pay for our mistakes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Though I use my phone only for taking calls and Google maps, I still miss it. After saying goodbyes, I was desperately browsing for &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com.au/gp/search?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;tag=anamica-22&amp;amp;linkCode=ur2&amp;amp;linkId=078ab941e58c5b60b4ee336ff375193a&amp;amp;camp=247&amp;amp;creative=1211&amp;amp;index=electronics&amp;amp;keywords=dual sim mobile phones&quot;&gt;Dual Sim Mobile Phones&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//ir-au.amazon-adsystem.com/e/ir?t=anamica-22&amp;amp;l=ur2&amp;amp;o=36&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; style=&quot;border:none !important; margin:0px !important;&quot; /&gt; on Amazon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the key features we use in most e-commerce platforms is sorting the product list either by price or new arrivals etc…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But from an software design and architectural perspective:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This sorting is a best example of Strategy Pattern&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;strategy-pattern---overview&quot;&gt;Strategy Pattern - Overview:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Defines a family of algorithms&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Encapsulates each algorithm&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Makes the algorithms interchangeable within that family.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Strategy lets the algorithm vary independently from clients that use it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;uml-and-case-diagram&quot;&gt;UML and Case Diagram&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://madhukumaar.com/assets/images/design-patterns/strategy/strategy-pattern-uml.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Strategy UML&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Participants of Strategy Pattern:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Strategy — declares an interface common to all supported algorithms. Context uses this interface to call the algorithm defined by a ConcreteStrategy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;ConcreteStrategy — implements the algorithm using the StrategyInterface.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Context — is configured with a ConcreteStrategy Object; maintains a reference to a Strategy object; may define an interface that lets Strategy access its data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Remember what I was talking above, these different sorting can be implemented as below:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-php highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;table class=&quot;rouge-table&quot;&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;rouge-gutter gl&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;lineno&quot;&gt;1
2
3
4
5
6
7
8
9
10
11
12
13
14
15
16
17
18
19
20
21
22
23
24
25
26
27
28
29
30
31
32
33
34
35
36
37
38
39
40
41
42
43
44
45
46
47
48
49
50
51
52
53
54
55
56
57
58
59
60
61
62
63
64
65
66
67
68
69
70
71
72
73
74
75
76
77
78
79
80
81
82
83
84
85
86
87
88
89
90
91
92
93
94
95
96
97
98
99
100
101
102
103
104
105
106
107
108
109
110
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;rouge-code&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;                &lt;span class=&quot;cp&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;?php&lt;/span&gt;
                
                &lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;// This can reduce lot of type errors&lt;/span&gt;
                &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;declare&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;strict_types&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;);&lt;/span&gt;
                
                &lt;span class=&quot;sd&quot;&gt;/**
                 * Strategy - Defines an interface common to all algorithms
                 * @param array $products
                 *
                 * @return array
                 */&lt;/span&gt;
                &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;interface&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;SorterInterface&lt;/span&gt;
                &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
                  &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;public&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;function&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;sort&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;array&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;$products&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;array&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
                &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
                
                
                &lt;span class=&quot;sd&quot;&gt;/**
                 * AscendingSort - Concrete Strategy - implements the algorithm using the Interface
                 */&lt;/span&gt;
                &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;class&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nc&quot;&gt;AscendingSort&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;implements&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;SorterInterface&lt;/span&gt;
                &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
                  &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;public&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;function&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;sort&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;array&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;$products&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;array&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
                    &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;asort&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;$products&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;);&lt;/span&gt;
                    &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;return&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;$products&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
                  &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
                &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
                
                &lt;span class=&quot;sd&quot;&gt;/**
                 * DescendingSort - Concrete Strategy - implements the algorithm using the Interface
                 */&lt;/span&gt;
                &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;class&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nc&quot;&gt;DescendingSort&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;implements&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;SorterInterface&lt;/span&gt;
                &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
                  &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;public&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;function&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;sort&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;array&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;$products&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;array&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
                    &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;arsort&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;$products&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;);&lt;/span&gt;
                    &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;return&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;$products&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
                  &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
                &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
                
                &lt;span class=&quot;sd&quot;&gt;/**
                 * DefaultSort - Concrete Strategy - implements the algorithm using the Interface
                 */&lt;/span&gt;
                &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;class&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nc&quot;&gt;DefaultSort&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;implements&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;SorterInterface&lt;/span&gt;
                &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
                  &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;public&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;function&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;sort&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;array&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;$products&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;array&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
                    &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;return&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;$products&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;// return unsorted&lt;/span&gt;
                  &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
                &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
                
                &lt;span class=&quot;sd&quot;&gt;/**
                 * ProductsSorter - sorts products - Context
                 */&lt;/span&gt;
                &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;class&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nc&quot;&gt;ProductsSorter&lt;/span&gt;
                &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
                  &lt;span class=&quot;sd&quot;&gt;/**
                  * @var SorterInterface
                  */&lt;/span&gt;
                  &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;private&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;$sorter&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
                
                  &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;public&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;function&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;setSorter&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;SorterInterface&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;$sorter&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
                  &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
                      &lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;$this&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;-&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;sorter&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;$sorter&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
                  &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
                
                  &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;public&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;function&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;selectSortingStrategy&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;string&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;$sortBy&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;){&lt;/span&gt;
                    &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;switch&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;$sortBy&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
                      &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;case&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;'ascending'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;
                        &lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;$this&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;-&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;setSorter&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;new&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;AscendingSort&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;());&lt;/span&gt;
                        &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;break&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
                
                      &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;case&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;'descending'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;
                        &lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;$this&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;-&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;setSorter&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;new&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;DescendingSort&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;());&lt;/span&gt;
                        &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;break&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
                
                      &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;default&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;
                        &lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;$this&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;-&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;setSorter&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;new&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;DefaultSort&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;());&lt;/span&gt;
                        &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;break&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
                    &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
                  &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
                
                  &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;public&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;function&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;sortProducts&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;array&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;$products&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;array&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
                      &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;return&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;$this&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;-&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;sorter&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;-&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;sort&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;$products&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;);&lt;/span&gt;
                  &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
                &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
                
                &lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;// Create Products array&lt;/span&gt;
                &lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;$products&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;array&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;
                  &lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;0&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;'Mobile'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;
                  &lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;'Camera'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;
                  &lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;2&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;'Flask'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;
                  &lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;3&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;'Coffee Mug'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;
                  &lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;4&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;'Laptop'&lt;/span&gt;
                &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;);&lt;/span&gt;
                
                &lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;// This sort method will come from FrontEnd through API call&lt;/span&gt;
                &lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;$sortBy&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;'ascending'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
                &lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;$sorter&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;new&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;ProductsSorter&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;();&lt;/span&gt;
                
                
                &lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;$sorter&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;-&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;selectSortingStrategy&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;$sortBy&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;);&lt;/span&gt;
                &lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;$sortedValues&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;$sorter&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;-&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;sortProducts&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;$products&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;);&lt;/span&gt;
                
                &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;print_r&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;$sortedValues&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;);&lt;/span&gt;
                
                &lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;$sortBy&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;'descending'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
                &lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;$sorter&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;-&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;selectSortingStrategy&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;$sortBy&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;);&lt;/span&gt;
                &lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;$sortedValues&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;$sorter&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;-&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;sortProducts&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;$products&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;);&lt;/span&gt;
                
                &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;print_r&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;$sortedValues&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;);&lt;/span&gt;
                
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This will produce the following result:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;table class=&quot;rouge-table&quot;&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;rouge-gutter gl&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;lineno&quot;&gt;1
2
3
4
5
6
7
8
9
10
11
12
13
14
15
16
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;rouge-code&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;    Array
    (
        [1] =&amp;gt; Camera
        [3] =&amp;gt; Coffee Mug
        [2] =&amp;gt; Flask
        [4] =&amp;gt; Laptop
        [0] =&amp;gt; Mobile
    )
    Array
    (
        [0] =&amp;gt; Mobile
        [4] =&amp;gt; Laptop
        [2] =&amp;gt; Flask
        [3] =&amp;gt; Coffee Mug
        [1] =&amp;gt; Camera
    )
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2019 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/test/design-patterns/strategy-pattern</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/test/design-patterns/strategy-pattern</guid>
        
        <category>design-pattern</category>
        
        <category>strategy-design-pattern</category>
        
        <category>php</category>
        
        <category>golang</category>
        
        <category>python</category>
        
        <category>typescript</category>
        
        
        <category>design-pattern</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
